Guide to the Frederick Hill Meserve Collection of Historical Portraits PR 231
New-York Historical Society
Frederick Hill Meserve Collection of Historical Portraits
circa 1860's
New-York Historical Society
PR 231
2.3 Linear feet (28 volumes)
Access Restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Scope and Contents
28 vols. Approx. 8000 images, each volume with list of portraits laid in the front; Brady photos.
Portraits, American.; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Portraits.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 1, 1913 (Volume 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Signed Frederick Hill Meserve, New York, November 1, 1953. Authors, artists, journalist and educators.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 2, 1913 (Volume 2)
  Authors, artists, journalist and educators.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 3, 1913 (Volume 3)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 4, 1913 (Volume 4)
  Prominent people in public and private life.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 5, 1913 (Volume 5)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 6, 1913 (Volume 6)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 7, 1913 (Volume 7)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 8, 1913 (Volume 8)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 9, 1913 (Volume 9)
  General Officers of the Union Army, War of the Rebellion.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 10, 1913 (Volume 10)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 11, 1913 (Volume 11)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 12, 1913 (Volume 12)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 13, 1913 (Volume 13)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 14, 1913 (Volume 14)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 15, 1913 (Volume 15)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 16, 1913 (Volume 16)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 17, 1913 (Volume 17)
  Regimental Officers, Union Army, War of the Rebellion.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 18, 1913 (Volume 18)
  Officers of the Union Navy, Caricatures, Miscellaneous portraits.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 19, 1913 (Volume 19)
  Confederate States of America, Miscellaneous.
- Historical Portraits, Volume 20, 1913 (Volume 20)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 21, 1913 (Volume 21)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 22, 1913 (Volume 22)
  Dramatic
- Historical Portraits, Volume 23, 1913 (Volume 23)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 24, 1913 (Volume 24)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 25, 1913 (Volume 25)
- Historical Portraits, Volume 26, 1913 (Volume 26)
  Celebrities of other countries, Miscellaneous
- Historical Portraits, Volume 27, 1913 (Volume 27)
  Lincolniana
- Historical Portraits, Volume 28, 1913 (Volume 28)
  Index